Contact

Corso Trieste, 165, Rome, 00199. menghwarprem@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/prem-s-menghwar-325b432b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Policy

Financial Management

Program Development

Languages

Italian (Professional Working)
English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Leadership and Communication Workshop

AMR Bridge Reviewer Graduation Certificate

Prem S. Menghwar

Postdoctoral Research Associate @ University of Virginia | PhD in Business Administration

Charlottesville, Virginia, United States

Summary

As a Postdoctoral Research Associate at the Darden School of Business, University of Virginia. I am conducting research on the dynamics of Stakeholder Theory in developing countries. In my research, I employ qualitative methodologies such as the analysis of case studies and the grounded theory approach. I have published a paper on "Creating Shared Value" in the International Journal of Management Reviews, which is Wiley's topcited and top downloaded of the year 2021-2022. I have also won the best Ph.D. Student paper award at the World Open Innovation Conference 2019. I hold a Ph.D. in Management from Luiss Guido Carli University, during which I was a visiting Ph.D. researcher at Boston College. I also earned a master's degree in Business Management from La Sapienza University in Rome and completed an Erasmus program at Södertörn University in Stockholm. I am passionate about advancing scholarship and practice in organizational purpose and Stakeholder Theory.

Experience

University of Virginia Darden School of Business Postdoctoral Research Associate October 2023 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Charlottesville, Virginia, United States

Luiss Guido Carli University
Research Fellow
September 2020 - August 2023 (3 years)
Rome, Latium, Italy

Research Fellowship - The Management of the Open Innovation Paradox: sharing vs protecting knowledge.

Professor Raffaele Oriani and Maria Isabella Leone

Boston College

Visiting Scholar

August 2021 - June 2023 (1 year 11 months)

United States

I worked with Professor Michael Pratt to learn how to do qualitative research!

Sukkur IBA University

6 years 2 months

Adviser Internationalisation and Exchange Program January 2019 - February 2023 (4 years 2 months)

Developed partnerships with Sapienza University, LIUC University, and LUISS University. Won ICM+ Erasmus grant with Sapienza University. Motivate and assist outgoing exchange students and visiting faculty members. Maintain effective communication between Sukkur IBA University and partner universities.

Coordinator Europe

January 2017 - January 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Rome, Latium, Italy

Initiated and strengthened collaboration with Sapienza University. I started with the first MoU for study exchange only with the faculty of economics.

Then, developed a university-level agreement that allowed student and faculty exchange. Maintained effective communication between the two institutes.

Developed exchange agreements with LIUC University and operationalized it.

European Horizons
President Sapienza University Chapter

April 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Rome Area, Italy

Preside over all General and Executive Board meetings, responsible for setting up the agenda for the meetings and invite guest speakers at EuH events. Responsibility to carry out the duties of the Executive Board members in the event of contravention of their constitutional duties. Represented Sapienza University Chapter at Fall Policy Convention in Germany and at DEYS Conference at College of Europe Bruges.

Rotaract Club of Islamabad Green Clty

President

August 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 2 months)

Remained active and in close liaison with civil society organizations. Founder of the club, Presided over all meetings of the club and its board of directors. Identified members' skills and interests and puts them to work in club

projects, trained new members and project staff.Leading on Pen Pal project in colloboration with Rotaract Club of Saint Leo University USA.

Education

LUISS Guido Carli University

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Business Administration and Management, General · (2018 - 2022)

Dipartimento di management - Università La Sapienza di Roma Master's Degree, Business Management · (September 2014 - July 2016)

Södertörn University

Master's Degree, Business Management · (2015 - 2016)